ABHISHEK JAMWAL

jamwal.ab@gmail.com

+1 365-778-7384

Mississauga, ON

LinkedInGitHubPortfoliowww.linkedin.com/in/abhishekj-21www.github.com/jamwalabWork in progress

Full Stack Web Developer, with a certificate from University of Toronto. Experienced in front-end and back-end design, database management and creating automated solutions. A team player, with good communication and problem-solving skills. Passionate about programming, with strong ability to design, build and maintain websites from ideation to production. An eager learner, with seven years of experience working in Supply Chain Industry.

Technical Skills

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Materialize

Backend: Node, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, React, Handlebars, API, PWA, OOP

Others: Visual Basic Application (VBA), Python (beginner), AWS

Projects

Smart-Fix | University of Toronto | HTML, CSS, Node, Express, MySQL, API, Handlebars, JavaScript Backend developer

- A website that helps customers connect with service providers for household repairs and maintenance.
- Allows users to register as a customer or service provider, with different functionality based on user type.
- Multiple service providers can bid for a job and the customer can assign the jobs by accepting one of the bids made.

ETA Tracker | Maersk | HTML, CSS, Node, Express, MySQL, API, Handlebars, JavaScript

Full stack developer

- Helps provide estimated time of arrival for shipments arriving at port and moving on rail.
- Allows users to request eta of shipping containers in bulk and display results in a table.

Calorie Tracker | University of Toronto | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API

Frontend developer

- Allows users to set calorie targets, track daily calorie consumption and track consumption with tables and graphs.
- Users can search food items for calorie data and recipes or manually add consumption data.

Relevant Experience

Maersk | Associate – Customs House Brokerage

September 2018 – Present

- Reduce the time required to track shipments by allowing containers to be searched in bulk with ETA Tracker.
- Built a VBA macro that checks customs entries to match customer requirements, thus achieving accuracy of over 97%.
- Designed VBA macro that tracks shipments for release and automatically assigns status at various stages of clearance.

APL Logistics | Senior Analyst – Global Trade Compliance

July 2016 – June 2018

- Developed and maintained trade compliance database content of multiple countries with MySQL, xml and excel.
- Built a VBA macro that helped reduce the time required to compile data for the database by 80%.

Molex | Analyst – Trade & Customs

August 2015 - June 2016

• Maintained HS code database of the products on SAP system for various countries.

Aptean | Analyst – Global Trade Content

February 2014 – August 2015

- Design backend process to capture trade compliance data from customs websites of different countries.
- Maintain trade compliance database of multiple countries and test the deployed code before moving it to production.

Education and certifications

University of Toronto, Toronto, ON Certificate – Full Stack Web Development April 2021 - September 2021

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Birla Institute of Management Technology, Greater Noida, India

July 2020

Post Graduate Diploma in Management (International Business) in Operations

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

July 2005 - June 2009

July 2011 - June 2013

Bachelor of Engineering - Electronics and Telecommunication